Guide to the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church records 2009.011
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 5: Pastors, 1816-2011; 4.75 Linear Feet
  - Sub-series 5.1: Rev. Theodore L. Cuyler, 1816-circa 1980s; 1 Linear Feet in one record carton
    - Section D: Portraits, circa 1850s-1920s
      - Portraits of Cuyler, circa 1870s-1900s (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Portrait of "The Three Theodores", 1892 (Box 34, Folder -)
      - Portraits of Theodore L. Cuyler the Third and others, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Section E: Other items, 1816-1974
      - The Christian's Inheritance... by Clarke, and envelope annotated by Cuyler, 1816-1818, circa 1880s-1900s (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Louisa Frances Cuyler diary, 1831-1834 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Temperance broadside, 1842 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Cuyler clipping, 1867 (Box 34, Folder -)
      - Cuyler and Sarah F. Smiley, 1872, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Anniversary and retirement service programs, 1885-1890 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Calling cards and invitations, circa 1880s-1900s (Box 17, Folder 23)
        Includes Rev. Cuyler, Mrs. Cuyler, Miss Mathiot and Arthur Reese Proal (in an enveloped labeled "Mrs. Eliza Davidson"), and Lafayette Avenue Church
      - Clippings - About Cuyler, 1890-1978 (Box 17, Folder 24)
        Includes an issue of The Quill (vol. 1 no 4. - April 1893)
      - The Evangelist - Theodore L. Cuyler the Third clipping, 1895 (Box 34, Folder -)
      - Theodore L. Cuyler memorial booklet, 1909 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - "Theodore Ledyard Cuyler: Friends of Lincoln and of Mankind" typescript, circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Cuyler visiting London, circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Sub-series 5.2: Rev. David Gregg, 1872-1911; 0.5 Linear Feet in nine folders
    The sub-series contains three volumes of bound, handwritten sermons by Gregg. The sermons, dating from 1872 to around 1884, were written and delivered while Gregg was pastor of the Third Reformed Presbyterian Church in Manhattan. Also included is a hymnal card from the Third Reformed Presbyterian Church (circa 1870s-1880s), two folders of published sermons (circa 1890-1911), documents related to this call to the LAPC (1890), a program for a lecture entitled "The Consecration of Music to the Service of Religion" (1893), a poem written by LAPC Elder A.G. Van Cleve in honor of Gregg departing the LAPC (1904), and a letter from Gregg to John R. Sager (1917).
    A letter from Gregg to then-current pastor Cleland B. McAfee regarding the church's music and new organ is housed in the Music and organ series (1910).
    - Handwritten sermons (3 volumes), 1872-circa 1884 (Box 21, Folder 24-26)
    - Third Reformed Presbyterian Church hymnal card, circa 1870s-1880s (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Call to LAPC, 1890 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Portraits, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Sermons (2 folders), circa 1890-1911 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
    - "The Consecreation of Music to the Service of Religion" lecture program, 1893 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Poem commemorating Gregg leaving the LAPC, 1904 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Composed by A.G. Van Cleve
    - Letter to John R. Sanger, 1917 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 5.3: Rev. Cleland B. McAfee, 1901-circa 1960s; 0.5 Linear Feet in six folders and one framed photograph
    Contains a family scrapbook (1901-1912, 1974), correspondence (1907), reports of the pastor (1908, circa 1910), two sermons ("The Book of Books" and "The Tonic of Prayer," 1911), a typescript written by McAfee's daughter Mildren McAfee Horton on her childhood in the church (circa 1950s), and a photocopy of hymnal sheet music composed and written by McAfee (circa 1960s). The correspondence folder also includes a photographic portrait of George T. Purvis and minutes for a special meeting of the Board of Deacons.
    A letter from former pastor David Gregg to McAfee regarding the church's music and new organ is housed in Series 11: Music and organ (1910). Correspondence between McAfee and Henry Logan is housed in Series 7: Session, Board of Trustees, and financial records (1935-1939).
    Arranged chronologically
    - McAfee family scrapbook, 1901-1912, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 47)
      Includes 1993 letter
    - Installation of Cleland B. McAfee group photograph, 1906 (Box 35, Folder -)
      Includes McAfee, Theodore L. Cuyler, David Gregg, Robert W. Anthony, and George H. Lunn.
    - McAfee portraits, 1906-circa 1930s (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 49)
      Primarily with Caleb V. Smith, also includes portrait of George T. Purvis and minutes for a special meeting of the Board of Deacons
    - Reports of the pastor, 1908, circa 1910 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Sermons, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 51)
      "The Book of Books" and "The Tonic of Prayer"
    - Typescript by Mildred McAfee Horton, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Hymnal sheet music by McAfee, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Sub-series 5.4: Rev. Charles C. Albertson, 1902-1959; 0.25 Linear Feet in nine folders
    The sub-series documents Rev. Charles C. Albertson's time as pastor of the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church (LAPC). It includes clippings (1902-1959), correspondence (1919-1959), four sermons (1920-1940), a bookplate belonging to his wife Permelia Hogg Albertson (circa 1900s), hymns and prayers (circa 1920s), a typescript entitled "They Saw the Emperor" with handwritten edits, a service book which was presented to Rev. Frank L. Gosnell by Albertson (1925), his letter of resignation as pastor of the LAPC (1928), and a historical typescript documenting his time as pastor at the LAPC (circa 1957). The series also includes the minutes for the Pastoral Committee which selected Albertson as pastor of the LAPC (1912).
    A letter from Albertson to then current Pastor Knight is housed in the correspondence file of Sub-series 5.6: Rev. George L. Knight.
    - Pastoral Committee minutes, 1912 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      Journal containing meeting minutes of the committee which selected Rev. Albertson to become pastor of LAPC
    - Clippings, 1902-1959 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Bookplate belonging to Permelia Hogg Albertson, circa 1900s (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1919-1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Sermons, 1920-1940 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      "The Greatest Mystery" (1920), "The Holy Night" (1920), "He Who Troubleth Us" (1922), "I Want to be Happy" (1940)
    - Hymns and prayers, circa 1920s (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "They Saw the Emperor" typescript with handwritten edits, circa 1920s (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Albertson portraits, circa 1920s (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Service book, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Resignation letter and clipping, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Historical typescript, circa 1957 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      Probably produced for centennial celebration
  - Sub-series 5.5: Rev. Alvin E. Magary, 1929-1964; 0.5 Linear Feet in nine folders and one framed photograph
    The sub-series documents Rev. Alvin E. Magary's time as pastor of the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church (LAPC). It includes documents relating to his selection as pastor (including correspondence, Session meeting minutes, service of installation program, and a clipping which includes an image of Magary after preaching his first sermon at the LAPC, 1929-1930), a sketch of Magary featured in the Brooklyn Eagle Magazine (1930), a sermon entitled "Shall the Republic Perish?" (1931), documents relating to his marriage (1938), Christmas cards (1943-1956), clippings documenting a burglary and attack on Magary and his wife (1947), sermon typescripts on notecards (1954-1957), retirement clippings (1957), a historical typescript on his time as pastor (circa 1957), and documents relating to his memorial service (1964).
    Correspondence from Magary to the Session is housed in Series 7: Session, Board of Trustees, and financial records.
    - Call to LAPC, 1929-1930 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Installation of Alvin E. Magary group photographs, 1930 (Box 35, Folder -)
      Two photographs, one framed. Includes Magary, Cleland B. McAfee, Charles C. Albertson, Basil D. Hall, Frank L. Gosnell, Robert W. Anthony, John E. Steen, and F. Raymond Clee.
    - Sermon: "Shall the Republic Perish", 1931 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Marriage, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Magary portraits, 1930s-1950s (Box 21, Folder 18)
      Includes wife Marion Clayton Magary
    - Margary's Christmas cards and letters, 1943-1956 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Attack clippings, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Margary sermons, 1954-1957 (Box 27, Folder 21)
      It is possible that the undated sermons in this file are actually Rev. Knight's sermons from the late 1950s.
    - Retirement clippings, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Historical typescript, circa 1957 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Memorial service and obituaries, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Sub-series 5.6: Rev. George L. Knight, 1952-1995; 1.5 Linear Feet in one record carton, eight folders, and one framed photograph
    The sub-series documents Rev. George L. Knight's time as pastor of the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church (LAPC), with material dating from 1952 to 1995. It includes, but is not limited to, a photograph documenting the installation of Rev. Knights as pastor (1957), four folders of sermons (1957-1982), correspondence (1959-1981), daily diaries (1963-1982), and a booklet commemorating his memorial service (1995).
    Additional sermons by Rev. Knight can be found in Sub-series 10.3: McWilliams family papers. Also, some undated sermons which have been filed under Rev. Alvin E. Magary (sub-series 5.5) may actually be Rev. Knight's sermons from the late 1950s.
    - "The Creative use of Hymns in Worship" by Knight, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      Union Seminary Quarterly Review, vol. VII no. 4
    - Service Book, 1956 (Box 28, Folder -)
    - Installation of George L. Knight group photograph, 1957 (Box 35, Folder -)
      Includes Knight, Alvin E. Magary, Norman S. DeWolfe, John Van Zanten, Phillips P. Elliott, Charles E. Souter, David D. Cockcroft, and Paul A. Wolfe.
    - Knight - Personal, 1957-1962 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      Includes photograph
    - Knight sermons (3 folders), 1957-1973 (Box 27, Folder 24-26)
    - Knight sermons, 1973-1982 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Yearbooks / Daily diaries (20 volumes), 1963-1982 (Box 28, Folder -)
      There is no 1964 book, and two books for 1977
    - Holy Bibles (2 volumes), 1964, 1982 (Box 28, Folder -)
    - Memorial service booklet, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 5.7: Rev. Jeffrey A. Vamos (Interim Pastor), 1990-1992; 0.25 Linear Feet in 16 folders
    The sub-series is composed of administrative files which were maintained by Interim Pastor Rev. Jeffrey A. Vamos, dating from 1990 to 1992.
    Related files can be found in Series 7: Session, Board of Trustees, and financial records.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Bible Study, circa 1990 (Box 26, Folder 53)
      See also: Social Action/Peacemaking folder
    - Building use forms, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 54)
    - Daily News, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 55)
    - Memos to Elders, Parishioners, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 56)
    - Persian Gulf, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 57)
    - Resumes/Professional information, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 58)
    - Sexuality Report, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 59)
    - Social Action/Peacemaking, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 60)
      See also: Bible Study folder
    - Sound System, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 61)
    - Special programs/projects, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 62)
    - Stewardship, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 63)
    - To-do forms, circa 1990 (Box 26, Folder 64)
    - Upcoming to publicize, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 65)
    - Wedding: Sweet/Quach - June 30, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 66)
    - Music and Worship Committee, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 67)
    - Youth Ministers, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 68)
  - Sub-series 5.8: Rev. David W. Dyson, 1992-2011; 0.1 Linear Feet in one folder
    The sub-series consists of material related to Rev. David W. Dyson, dating from 1992 to 2011. It includes four sermons, church flyers, clippings, and a program for Dyson's ten year anniversary testimonial brunch program. It also contains recordings of the community tribute to Dyson at the Irondale Center (October 2, 2011) and Dyson's last service (October 30, 2011) on two DVDs and five Mini Digital Video cassettes.
    - Rev. David W. Dyson file, 1992-2002 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      Contains four sermons, church flyers, clippings, and Dyson's ten year anniversary testimonial brunch program
    - Dyson community tribute and last service recordings, 2011 (Box 41, Folder 14)
- Series 6: Membership, marriage, and baptismal records, 1853-1995; 1.75 Linear Feet in two record cartons
  The series contains LAPC records documenting church membership, marriages, baptisms, and deaths, dating from 1853 to 1995. Several 19th century registers were maintained by Rev. Culyer and are written in his hand. The series includes a register for the Market Street Church (Manhattan), where Cuyler served as pastor prior to coming to the LAPC. Additional lists of members can be found in Series 8: Church manuals and calendars.
  - Market Street Church baptism, marriage, and membership journal, 1853-1877 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Written in Cuyler's hand
  - Alphabetical member register revised, 1857-circa 1880s (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Register of members, 1857-1897 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Register of members and baptisms, 1858-1868 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Register of members, circa 1850s-1890s (Box 34, Folder -)
    Oversized; written in Cuyler's hand
  - Member address directory, 1869 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Register of baptisms, 1869-1890 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Includes 1938 letter
  - Register of members, 1874-1895 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Member address directory, circa 1875 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    U.S. Christian Commission journal; written in Cuyler's hand
  - Member address directory, 1877 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Marriage certificate: Stewart M. Steven and Agnes Gorden, 1877 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Marriage journal, 1878-1909 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Member address directory, 1881 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Member address directory, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Matilda Sherwood information card, circa 1890s-1910s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Register of members and baptisms, 1891-1905 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Register of baptisms, 1893-1896 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Official directory, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Charter members list, 1901-1909
  - Dedication and baptism cards, 1901-1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Register of members, marriages, and baptisms, 1906-1915 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    #6851-8319
  - Membership statistics, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Register of elders, members, baptisms, and marriages, 1915-1958 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Member list, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Members for fifty years or more, circa 1930 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Register of elders, members, baptisms, and marriages, 1939-1961 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Members and addresses, 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Ella Danielson Holm membership transfer card, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Park Presbyterian Church - list of original members, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Church directory, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Baptisms, deaths, marriages, and new members, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Membership forms, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Membership records for bulletin, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - To be noted and recorded (3 folders), 1961-1969 (Box 29, Folder 5-7)
    Member addresses
  - Membership book, 1962-1970 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Membership and baptism records, 1964-1973 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Membership and baptism forms (4 folders), 1964-1975 (Box 15, Folder 16-19)
  - Ruth M. Strang funeral card, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - List of members - 25 years of more with the church, circa 1974 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Baptisms, marriages, deaths, and new members, 1983, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Presbytery of New York City directory, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Register of marriages and John Okike certificate of transfer, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Directory of members and friends, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 25)
- Series 7: Session, Board of Trustees, and financial records, 1854-1995; 0.7 Linear Feet
  The series contains records of the LAPC Session, in addition to financial records and files relating to the LAPC Board of Trustees, dating from 1854 to 1995.
  It contains annual reports dating from 1879-1920, in the form of manuscripts (handwritten), typescripts, and published booklets.
  Financial records are primarily composed of Treasurer's reports and account books, dating from 1854 to 1915. Financial records dating from after 1915 have been retained by LAPC.
  The series includes a two folders of letters sent to and from the Session and the Board of Trustees, dating from 1879 to 1953.
  Finally, the series contains a small set of Session adminstrative files, primarily concerning Session committees, dating from 1990 to 1995. Related files can be found in Sub-series 5.7: Rev. Jeffrey A. Vamos (Interim Pastor).
  The series is roughly arranged as follows: Annual reports, by-laws, financial records, Board of Trustees and Session correspondence, and Session administrative files.
  - Annual reports - manuscripts/typescripts, 1879-1889 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports - manuscripts/typescripts, 1891-1896 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports - booklets, 1890-1901 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Annual reports - typescripts, 1908-1920 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Annual report - booklet, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - By-laws, 1892, 1896, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Pew rentals, 1854-1900 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Account book, 1860-1904 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Financial reports, 1865-1915 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1868-1913 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Account book, 1882-1883 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1879-1937 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Includes John T. Underwood and correspondence with Session regarding music and choir (1879)
  - Session - Letters, 1891-1953 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Henry Logan and Rev. McAfee, and Rev. Magary and the Session, 1935-1939 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Found in a copy of The Ruling Elder by Cleland B. McAfee (LAPC BX9195 .M25 1931)
  - Christian Education Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Personnel Committee, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Presbytery of New York City, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Social Concerns Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Standing Committees of the Session, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 13)
- Series 8: Church manuals and calendars, 1855-1923, circa 1980; 0.2 Linear Feet in five folders
  The series contains pulished church manuals and calendars, dating from 1855 to the 1980s. It includes a Park Congregational Church manual (1855) and a Park Presbyterian Church manual (1860). The manuals contain historical sketches, rules and regulations, and membership rolls.
  - Manuals, 1855-1899 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Calendars, 1896-1899 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Manuals and membership rolls, 1904-1909 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Manuals and membership rolls, 1916-1923 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - New member booklet, circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 31)
- Series 9: Historical files, 1858-2004; 0.75 Linear Feet in one record carton
  The series contains historical material which had been collected by the church, dating from 1858 to 2004. One item of note is the certificate of incorporation of the Park Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn (1858). Other subjects include the Cumberland Street Church (1897-1905), the Olivet Presbyterian Church (1901-1941), the Gregg Chapel (1916-1933), church attendance (1931-1950), Marianne Moore (1958-1990), and the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn (1970s-1980s). Several church groups are represented in the files, including the Brooklyn City Mission and Tract Society, Cuyler Mission Band, Men's Bible Class, Women's Federation, Young Men's League, and the Young Men's Literary Society.
  - 75th Anniversary, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Regarding first telephone in Brooklyn
  - 100th Anniversary, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 125th Anniversary, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Advertisement, circa 1910s (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Artwork, 1970s (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Assistant Pastors, 1882-1957 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Attendance, 1931-1950 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Bequests, circa 1900s-1940s (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn City Mission and Tract Society, 1919 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Certificate of Incorporation - Park Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn, 1858 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1875-1964 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Henry Hand, 1892, 1906 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Cumberland Street Church, 1897-1905 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Cuyler Mission Band, 1888-1895 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Cuyler Mission Band - The Zenana No. 1 and 3, 1869 (Box 34, Folder -)
  - Deacons, 1894-1957 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Dinner menus, 1922-1923 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Easter card signed by Rev. Knight and Elders, circa 1960s (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Ephemera, 1906-1977 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Financial Aid, 1905-1906 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Fort Greene, 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Fort Greene - Martyr's monument, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Fort Greene - Walking tours, circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Fundraising, 1971, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Gregg Chapel - Italian Congregation, 1913, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Gregg Chapel - Photographs, 1916, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Habitat for Humanity calendar, 2004 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Handbook, 1907 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - History of the Church, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Home Department, 1905-1917 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Homecoming Day, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Lafayette Record, 1907-1940s (Box 26, Folder 30)
    Includes Cuyler letter
  - List of contents of package received from Mr. Healy's son, circa 1920 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - MaCauley's paper, circa 1850s-1860s (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Marianne Moore, 1958-1987 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    Includes photographs and negative
  - Marianne Moore commemorative stamp, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Members - Obituaries and memorials, circa 1870s-1976 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Members - Prominent members of the past, circa 1970s (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Men's Bible Class, 1915-1917 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Men's Club, 1917-1921 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Ministers, 1930s-1960s (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Note from Mrs. S. Theodore Dauchy to Mr. Egg, circa 1910s (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Nursing homes, 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Officers / Staff, 1900-1958 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Olivet Presbyterian Church, 1901-1941 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Pastors - Notes on pastors, possibly for use in a play, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Play script, circa 1960s (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Postcards, 1905-1907 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - "Recollections" by Willoughby Powell, circa 1930s (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - Responsive Service books, 1893 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - Responsive Service books, 1897, 1906 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - Silent Auction Gala catalog, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Synodical Homes Missions, 1909-1910 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - Woman's Board of Home Missions of the Presbyterian Church, USA - Young People's Work pamphlet, 1916 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - Women, 1909-1989 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    Includes photographs
  - Young Men's League, circa 1890s (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Young Men's Literary Society, 1902 (Box 26, Folder 51)
  - Zeppelin L49 - Piece of outer skin of zeppelin brought down at Bourbonne-les-Bains, October 22, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 52)
- Series 10: Elders and Administrators, 6.7 Linear Feet